# Michael Kithinji

### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Gmail Github LinkedIn Twitter Medium Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with a background in developing efficient software applications in a global market. 3+ years of industry experience, including mentoring 10+ junior developers to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline. Strong skills include Database management and PostgreSQL and Ruby.

# SKILLS

- Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3.
- Back-End: Ruby On Rails, PostgreSQL.
- Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools.
- Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring
- Languages: English Advanced.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

### Full Stack Web Developer & Mentor

September 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 30+ full-stack projects independently and via pair programming.

- <u>Budget App</u> A budget management app built with Rails and Devise gem, with a clean and user-friendly interface designed with HTML, CSS and Ruby.
- **Finance App** [Finance APP] is a react app that displays a list of stocks and services; when a user clicks on a stock, the app displays a list of companies that can be filtered using the search bar.
- <u>JavaScript Bootcamp</u> This is a JavaScript bootcamp capstone project. The project is responsive to mobile devices. Built with: (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs).

# MICROVERSE

Remote

### Mentor (Volunteer)

January 2023 - Present

- Mentoring a team of 10+ junior web developers, delivering technical support and guidance through code reviews conducted via Zoom sessions.
- Providing tailored advice and motivational strategies, contributing to a 25% increase in program longevity and a 15% boost in student engagement.

#### UNITED STATE OF AFRICA

Nairobi, Kenya

### **Backend Node.Js Engineer**

January 2022 - Dec 2022

- Provided guidance and actionable strategies for sustaining long-term engagement in the program, resulting in a 25% increase in user retention over a six-month period.
- Coached junior developers, leading detailed code reviews for a 15% code quality boost and 20% fewer post-release defects.

#### **EDUCATION**

**MICROVERSE** 

January 2023 – present

# Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spending 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

CHUKA UNIVERSITY

### Degree, Concentration

Microverse- Full-Stack Developer.

September 2021